<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The parable of the three jackdaws, &amp;c.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1696</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 21 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A55713</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P326</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R6017</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13087491</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13087491</idno>
            <idno type="VID">97317</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A55713)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 97317)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 747:41)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The parable of the three jackdaws, &amp;c.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for R. Baldwin ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1696]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Advertisement: p. 4.</note>
                  <note>An allegorical tract on English government and politics.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1689-1702 --  Anecdotes</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:97317:1"/>
            <head>THE PARABLE OF THE <hi>Three Jackdaws,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
            <p>THERE was a Time when the <hi>Feathered Commonwealth</hi> fell into Great Diſorder about Chuſing a Succeſſor to the <hi>Eagle,</hi> whoſe Advanced Years Portended the Fall of his Scepter, and the Diſputes which happened amongſt the ſeveral Pretenders, did mightily Perplex the <hi>Kingdom of Birds,</hi> who were in doubt, whether the <hi>Eagle</hi> had any <hi>Genu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ine Off-ſpring.</hi> The <hi>Magpies,</hi> who had an Inve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terate Malice againſt the <hi>Blackbirds</hi> and <hi>Nightin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gales,</hi> becauſe they were better lik't than them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves on the Account of their Harmonious Notes, and Innocent Nature, improv'd the op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity to make Intereſt with <hi>the Jackdaws and Cuccows,</hi> to Settle the Succeſſion on a <hi>Noted Bird,</hi> which was reckon'd Brother to the <hi>Eagle,</hi> becauſe Hatch'd in the ſame Neſt; but a Mortal Enemy to the <hi>Nightingales</hi> and <hi>Blackbirds,</hi> and accus'd of a Confederacy with the <hi>Storks</hi> and <hi>Kites,</hi> to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tray the Winged Nation to the Birds of Prey. The <hi>Magpies</hi> were frequently told of this, and Remonſtrances were entred againſt their Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding, as deſtructive to the whole <hi>Volatile Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pire;</hi> but they turn'd the Deaf Ear to every thing that was ſaid to 'em; for being uſed to feed upon <hi>Carrion,</hi> they delighted in Slaughter. In proceſs of time the <hi>Eagle</hi> died, and his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, the <hi>Friend to the Magpies,</hi> Succeeded: As ſoon as he Mounted the Throne, the <hi>Magpies</hi> Chatter'd for Joy, the <hi>Jackdaws Caw'd,</hi> and the <hi>Cuccows</hi> made Proteſtations of Loyalty in their Uſual Note; but he was ſcarcely Seated on the Throne, when the Region of the Air was fill'd with Birds of Prey, the <hi>Screech-Owls</hi> began to quarrel with the <hi>Jackdaws,</hi> and the <hi>Cormorants</hi> pretended a Right to the Neſts of the <hi>Mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pies.</hi> In the mean time, though they could not agree amongſt themſelves, yet all of them uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted againſt the <hi>Nightingales</hi> and <hi>Blackbirds,</hi> who, by this means, were forced to Retire to the So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litary Groves, where they Chirpt and Warbled out their own Misfortunes. The Affairs of the Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged Empire being in this poſture, a <hi>Generous Fal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>con,</hi> as he was call'd by ſome, or the True Off<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpring of the <hi>Eagle,</hi> as reckoned by others, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing mov'd with compaſſion towards the Injured Birds attempted their Relief; but the <hi>Magpies</hi> and <hi>Jackdaws,</hi> with their Adherents the <hi>Cuccows,</hi> were ſo much Incenſed againſt the Generous <hi>Fal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>con,</hi> becauſe of his favourable Inclinations to the <hi>Nightingales</hi> and <hi>Blackbirds,</hi> that they ſummon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed together their Friends the <hi>Rooks,</hi> and joyning with the <hi>Storks</hi> and <hi>Kites,</hi> Oppreſſed the poor <hi>Falcon,</hi> with his ſmall Retinue; and having Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barouſly deſtroyed them, the <hi>Eagles</hi> Brother lookt upon his Throne as ſurer than ever; and the <hi>Magpies, Jackdaws,</hi> and <hi>Cuccows,</hi> concluding that they had inſur'd his Favour, by this New Merit, preſs'd on to deſtroy the <hi>Blackbirds</hi> and <hi>Nightingals.</hi> But all of a ſudden, when they
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:97317:2"/>thought themſelves ſecure, the <hi>Night-Owls</hi> and <hi>Cormorants,</hi> with the <hi>Storks</hi> and <hi>Kites</hi> their Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herents, having been a long time diſpoſſeſt of their Neſts by the <hi>Magpies</hi> and <hi>Jackdaws,</hi> and their followers the <hi>Rooks</hi> and <hi>Cuccows,</hi> reſolv'd to come to a Trial of Skill with them, upon which the <hi>Magpies</hi> came to have ſome <hi>REMORSE</hi> for then Barbarous Treatment of the Innocent <hi>Black<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>birds;</hi> and, abating ſomething of the uſual harſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of their Note, began to call <hi>Mag, Mag, poor Mag, a Cup of Sack for poor fainting Mag;</hi> and the <hi>Jackdaws</hi> Caw'd to the <hi>Blackbirds,</hi> in a Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der Note than before, bewaild their Former Seve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, and invited the <hi>Nightingales</hi> and <hi>Blackbirds</hi> to joyn with them, againſt the <hi>Kites, Cormorants,</hi> and <hi>Screech-Owls.</hi> The <hi>Eagles</hi> Brother being a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fraid of the Conſequences of ſuch an Union, came alſo to a Parley with the <hi>Blackbirds</hi> and <hi>Nightin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gales,</hi> and offered them <hi>fair Quarter,</hi> provided they would concur towards the procuring of an <hi>Authentick Act</hi> at the General Diet of the Wing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Empire, to ſecure his Followers in the Poſſeſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of their Neſts for all time coming; the <hi>Ama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zed Blackbirds</hi> being ſurpriz'd with this mighty Change, and having been wretchedly torn by the Talons of both Parties, knew not whom to truſt; but the <hi>Eagles Brother</hi> being poſſeſt of the Throne, decency oblig'd them to make Civil Replies: but ſome of the <hi>BATTS</hi> which frequented the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany of the <hi>Blackbirds,</hi> engaged too far with the <hi>Cormorant</hi>-Intereſt, and by this time both Parties own'd the Poſſeſſor of the Throne for a True Ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gle: Having gain'd his Point ſo far, he reſolv'd to puſh on his Fortune, and being provok't with the Behaviour of the <hi>Magpies,</hi> he deſign'd to put their Pretenſions of Loyalty to the Touch-ſtone, and commanded them to publiſh his Imperial E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict, giving Liberty to all the Subjects of the Airy Regions to Warble out the Praiſes of their Great Creator, in ſuch Notes as Nature had furniſht 'em with, <hi>It being highly unreaſonable to ſay, that the</hi> Canary-bird <hi>was no Bird, becauſe ſhe could not Croak like the</hi> Raven, <hi>or that the</hi> Nightingale <hi>was no Subject of the Winged Empire, becauſe ſhe could not chatter like the</hi> Magpy.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Magpies</hi> and <hi>Jacks</hi> were Thunder-ſtruck at tho hearing of this unlookt-for Command, and Moſt of 'em did <hi>S<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>LLENLY</hi> refuſe it: yet ſome of the <hi>Magpies,</hi> and the <hi>Swallows</hi> which <hi>neſtled about the Altars</hi> thought fit to comply, but the <hi>Metro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>politan-Magpy,</hi> and Six of the reſt did poſitively refuſe to obey the <hi>Eagle,</hi> who did thereupon Commit them to his Imperial Priſon. Then no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing was to be heard but <hi>Alas poor Mag, a Cup of Sack for Mag:</hi> and on the other hand, the <hi>Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>morants</hi> and <hi>Kites</hi> cried, <hi>A Rope for Mag, Mag, Mag, a Halter for Mag:</hi> and the <hi>Blackbirds</hi> and <hi>Nightingales,</hi> though they were ſomething con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerned at the Misfortune of the <hi>Magpies,</hi> yet could not but ſay, that <hi>Mag</hi> was ſerv'd accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>er Deſerts: but the <hi>Jackdaws</hi> and <hi>Cuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cows,</hi> with their Allies the <hi>Rooks,</hi> did ſo much di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſturb the <hi>Eagles</hi> Quiet; with their <hi>Cawing</hi> and <hi>Croaking,</hi> that he Releaſed the <hi>Magpies,</hi> but pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſued his Deſign of Eſtabliſhing a Tyranny in the Regions of the Air; and, in order to accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſh his Deſign, did enter into a Confederacy with the <hi>V<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>LT<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>RE,</hi> Reſolv'd to Diſinherit the <hi>Generous She-Eagle</hi> of his own Race, and to Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe a <hi>Counterfeit He-Eagle</hi> upon the Nation of the Birds; which did ſo much provoke the Fea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther'd Commonwealth, that they agreed, with the Aſſiſtance of a <hi>Genuine Eagle,</hi> of the True Impe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rial Neſt, who had the Generous <hi>She-Eagle,</hi> above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, to his Mate, to Curb the Tyrannical <hi>Eagle,</hi> and prevent his Impoſing <hi>an Ostrich</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of an <hi>Eagle</hi> upon the Winged Empire. Many of the <hi>Magpies</hi> and <hi>Jackdaws,</hi> with all the <hi>Black<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>birds</hi> and <hi>Nightingales,</hi> Joyn'd in the Invitation to the <hi>Young Eagle,</hi> who taking his Flight from beyond-Sea, did happily Alight in the Imperial Grove; and being Joyn'd with a Promiſcuous Flock of <hi>Blackbirds, Jackdaws, Nightingales,</hi> and ſome <hi>Rooks,</hi> put the <hi>Kites,</hi> and <hi>Cormorants,</hi> and <hi>Old Eagle</hi> to Flight; who, after he had Rooſted a while in his Imperial Neſt, abandoned the ſame, and Fled Beyond-Sea with the <hi>Oſtrich his Mate,</hi> and the Counterfeit-Eagle her Suppoſed-Son, to the <hi>Vulture</hi>'s-Grove.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Eagle</hi> having thus taken his flight, the <hi>Magpies</hi> began to relent, and to wiſh that thing had not come to that Extremity; for the <hi>Jackda<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and they became now apprehenſive, that they were in as much danger of loſing their Neſts, by the <hi>Blackbirds</hi> and <hi>Nightingals,</hi> as they had for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly been by the <hi>Kites</hi> and <hi>Cormorants,</hi> becauſe the <hi>Young Eagle</hi> who came from beyond <hi>Sea,</hi> was Judged to have a mighty kindneſs for the <hi>Black<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>birds
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:97317:2"/>and Nightingals,</hi> and his Mate, the Generous <hi>ſhe-Eagle</hi> had no averſion to them, and thus it came to paſs that the <hi>Metropolitical Magpy,</hi> who had been the Ringleader of thoſe who oppos'd the old <hi>Eagle,</hi> and invited the young one to his Neſt, began to <hi>grow ſullen,</hi> and his Example in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fecting the reſt of the <hi>Maggs,</hi> the faction was divided amongſt themſelves, ſo that ſome of the <hi>Magpies and Jackdaws,</hi> were for acknowledging the young Eagle as Soveraign of the Birds, and others chattering ſtill upon the <hi>abdicated theme of paſſive obedience,</hi> alledg'd that the old <hi>Eagle</hi> had injury done him, and did all that they could to obſtruct the progreſs of the young <hi>Ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gles</hi> affairs, and having by the Intereſt of the <hi>Magpies,</hi> who own'd his Title, got an influence on his Councils, they advis'd him to disband the <hi>Blackbirds and Nightingals,</hi> who had flockt to him at his firſt coming over, and to govern his affairs by the advice of the <hi>Magpies and Jackdaws,</hi> and by this method they got his Court and his Camp fill'd with Rooks, who did ſtill retain a very great kindneſs for the old <hi>Eagle,</hi> and their ancient Cro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, the <hi>Cormorants</hi> and <hi>Kites,</hi> and did them kind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly offices as opportunity offered.</p>
            <p>In the mean time the <hi>Nightingals,</hi> and <hi>Black<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>birds</hi> of the <hi>Eagles antient Grove;</hi> had been ſo terribly infeſted by the <hi>Magpies, Jackdaws,</hi> and <hi>Rooks,</hi> and ſo miſchievouſly torn by the <hi>Talons</hi> of the <hi>Kites,</hi> and <hi>Cormorants</hi> their allies, that they lookt upon the <hi>Magpies as Harpies,</hi> and in a Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral <hi>diet of the Birds</hi> held for that Grove, Voted that the <hi>Magpies</hi> and their <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nderlings,</hi> the <hi>Jack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daws</hi> were the great and inſupportable grievance of the Winged Empire, and with one conſent diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>log'd them of their Neſts, ſo that the <hi>Maggs and Jacks hopt away in great Numbers,</hi> to the Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bouring Grove, chatter'd nothing but paſſive obe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dience and Nonreſiſtance, and the Injury done to the old <hi>Eagle,</hi> which ſtrengthened the faction of the <hi>Southern Magpies,</hi> and made the young <hi>Eagle</hi> very uneaſy in his Neſt; whence it came to paſs that the <hi>Magpy faction</hi> procur'd a Rebellion in the <hi>Northern Grove,</hi> under the Conduct of a <hi>Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chievous Rook,</hi> who being joyn'd by a <hi>Rabble</hi> of the <hi>Jackdaws, Kites, Cormorants,</hi> and <hi>Solan Geeſe,</hi> gave the young <hi>Eagles</hi> followers in that Grove a conſiderable Check, but the miſchievous <hi>Rook</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing peckt to death in the ſcuffle, the Rebellion was gradually appeas'd there; but the <hi>Northern Jackdaws</hi> and <hi>Solan Geeſe,</hi> with the abdicated <hi>Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pies,</hi> fill'd the <hi>Southern Grove</hi> with their querelous Notes, ſo that nothing was to be heard, but alas, <hi>poor Magg, Magg, Magg,</hi> is put out of her Neſt in the <hi>North,</hi> and muſt expect the ſame treat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in the <hi>South,</hi> except the old <hi>Eagle</hi> be recall'd. Whereupon that <hi>Tyrrannous</hi> bird conceiving good hopes of his affairs, did by the aſſiſtance of the <hi>Vulture,</hi> who lent him ſome bands of <hi>Storks, Kites,</hi> and <hi>Rooks,</hi> take his flight to St. <hi>Patricks Grove,</hi> where being Joyn'd by ſome <hi>Cormorants,</hi> and the <hi>Native Woodcocks;</hi> he quickly overſoread the whole Grove excepting ſome ſmall part of it, where a <hi>Colony of their Northern birds had fixt</hi> their Neſts, who made ſuch a ſtout Reſiſtance againſt the Tyrant <hi>Eagle,</hi> and his birds of prey, that the fame thereof eccho'd through the Regions of the Air, but the <hi>Southern Magpies</hi> and <hi>Jackdaws</hi> being influ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>enc'd by the <hi>Northern Harpies,</hi> and <hi>Solan-Geeſe</hi> ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructed the Relief of the <hi>Blackbirds</hi> of St. <hi>Patricks Grove</hi> ſo long, that they were well nigh undone, and the firſt relief they had ſent 'em being under the Conduct of a <hi>Villanous Rook,</hi> he was little leſs Noiſome to the <hi>Blackbirds,</hi> than the <hi>Kites</hi> and <hi>Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>morants,</hi> ſo that the young <hi>Eagle</hi> was oblig'd to fly thither in perſon, and not long after his Arri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>val, he gave the Tyrant <hi>Eagle</hi> and his followers ſuch a terrible overthrow by a <hi>purling brook;</hi> that the old one fled from St. <hi>Patricks Grove,</hi> and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>took himſelf again to the <hi>Vultures</hi> quarters, whilſt the <hi>Colones</hi> of the <hi>Northern Blackbirds</hi> and <hi>Night<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingals,</hi> did with inimitable Courage ſubdue the <hi>Woodcocks,</hi> and the young <hi>Eagles</hi> followers diſlog'd the <hi>Vultures</hi> and <hi>Cormorants</hi> from their Neſts, ſo that in a little time St. <hi>Patricks Grove</hi> was entirely recovered.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Vulture,</hi> by whoſe Counſels the abdicated <hi>Eagle</hi> had all along govern'd himſelf, perceiving that he was now quite driven from his Neſt, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved to attack the <hi>Flemmiſh Coppice;</hi> which had formerly been the Reſidence of the young <hi>Eagle,</hi> which oblig'd the Generous Bird to repair <hi>Beyond-Sea,</hi> for the defence of his ancient friends, but tho he Acted <hi>Wonders,</hi> yet his Counſels were betray'd by the friends of the <hi>Maggs and the Daws,</hi> and his Troops being chiefly Commanded by <hi>Rooks,</hi> the Birds of his retinue met with ſeveral Diſaſters, and at the ſame time the <hi>Kites</hi> and <hi>Cormorants,</hi> and
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:97317:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <hi>ſeditious Maggs,</hi> did all that they could to diſturb the repoſe of the Generous ſhe <hi>Eagle</hi> his Mate, whom they would fain have deſtroy'd in his ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence, but the <hi>faithful Magpies and moderate Jack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daws,</hi> with the <hi>Blackbirds</hi> and <hi>Nightingals,</hi> did unite ſo cordially for her defence, that their de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigns were diſappointed. Thus was the Generous young <hi>Eagle</hi> perplexed by <hi>Vultures, Storks,</hi> and <hi>Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>morants</hi> abroad, and <hi>Treacherous Magpies Jackdaws and Rooks</hi> at home, and chiefly becauſe they were apprehenſive of being outed by the <hi>Blackbirds,</hi> who whatever priviledges they had acquir'd in the <hi>North,</hi> they ſaid muſt content themſelves to build Neſts in the <hi>Eves of houſes in the</hi> South, <hi>where the Churches were the proper habitation of the Magpies and Jackdaws,</hi> Nor would they ſuffer the <hi>Nightin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gals</hi> and the <hi>Falcons,</hi> to have any command in the winged Army, that being the property of the <hi>Kites</hi> and <hi>Rooks,</hi> becauſe they did annually ſwear Allegiance to the <hi>Magpies</hi> and <hi>Jackdaws</hi> at the Altars, which the <hi>Falcons</hi> and <hi>Nightingals</hi> would never do.</p>
            <p>In the mean time the <hi>Generous ſhe Eagle</hi> died, which did ſo much grieve her faithful Mate, that the Kingdom of Birds, had well nigh loſt both their Soveraigns at once: However, he generouſly pluckt up his Courage, and conſidering that he was born for Empire, did ſcorn to be conquered by paſſion; and therefore reſolv'd that as he had defeated the <hi>Maws</hi> and the <hi>Gulls,</hi> belonging to the <hi>Vulture</hi> by Sea, he would have a Trial of Valour with him by Land, notwithſtanding his Alliance with the <hi>overgrown Raven of the</hi> Eaſt, ſo that taking another flight into the Continent, he diſlodged the <hi>Vulture</hi> from one of his chief Neſts, who thereupon became ſo much affraid of the young <hi>Eagles Talons,</hi> that he durſt not adventure on a fair War with him any more; but reſolv'd to ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>born ſome <hi>Night-Owls, Buzzards, Kites, Cormorants,</hi> and <hi>Cuccows,</hi> to aſſaſſinate the Generous <hi>Eagle</hi> in the dark, which he had attempted ſeveral times before, but laid the deſign ſo craftily now, that he was ſure it c<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>uld not miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>carry. And this taking effect he deſign'd to have de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy'd all the <hi>Blackbirds and Nightingals, with the faithful Magpies</hi> and moderate <hi>Jackdaws,</hi> and all the other loyal Birds in St. <hi>George</hi> St. <hi>Andrews,</hi> and St. <hi>Patricks Groves,</hi> and to have poſſeſt them for ever; with <hi>Vultures, Kites, Storks, Ravens, Rooks, Cormorants,</hi> and <hi>Magpies,</hi> and <hi>Jack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daws</hi> of his own ſtamp. However this <hi>conſpiracy</hi> being happily diſcovered by the <hi>Parrots,</hi> many of the <hi>Owls, Buzzards,</hi> and <hi>Cormorants,</hi> who were imployed to aſſaſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate the young <hi>Eagle</hi> were taken, and ſome of 'em ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered Death according to the Laws of the feathered Kingdom; <hi>three Cormorants</hi> firſt, and a little after <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Cuccows,</hi> who being drawn in by the <hi>Treacherous Magpies,</hi> and <hi>Jackdaws, three</hi> of the latter attended them to the place of their <hi>Exit,</hi> and Cawing to them in the old Note of paſſive obedience, deluded the poor <hi>Cuccows,</hi> and tel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling them that by vertue of the Authority which they had acquir'd by a long poſſeſſion of the Steepies; where no <hi>Blackbird</hi> had any right to come, they were conſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Lawful Prieſts of the winged Empire, and therefore <hi>abſolv'd</hi> them from the falſe imputation of guilt, for en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavouring to cut the young <hi>Eagles</hi> throat, for he was none of the Birds of <hi>Jupiters</hi> Neſt, and tho the Beetle had unluckily broke all the old <hi>Eagles</hi> Eggs, which were procreated betwixt him and the <hi>Italian Oſtrich;</hi> yet there was a time coming when they would find a ſafe repoſitory if not in <hi>Joves,</hi> yet in St. <hi>Peters Lapp,</hi> and oblige the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended <hi>Eagle,</hi> who was no other than a <hi>Geneva</hi> Bird, hatcht amongſt the ſhells, which one of the <hi>Roman</hi> Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perors gathered together as a Mark of Triumph on the <hi>Dutch Coaſt,</hi> to retire to the banks of <hi>Lake-Leman,</hi> in the faith of which the 2 <hi>ſilly Cuccows,</hi> did chearfully ſwallow their hempſeed, and crying <hi>Cuc-cow, Cuc-cow,</hi> the <hi>Jack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daws</hi> anſwered Caw, caw, caw, and then the <hi>Cuccows</hi> were choackt, at which the Loyal Birds were ſo much incens'd, that they have ſhut up 2 <hi>of the Jackdaws in a Cage;</hi> and are hunting after the other which is fled; ſo that in a little time, we may hap to ſee theſe <hi>Jackdaws</hi> follow the fate of the <hi>Cuccows,</hi> while all the <hi>Winged Empire, from the Impe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rial Eagle to the Wren,</hi> are aſſociated to defend the Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous young <hi>Eagle,</hi> as a true bird of the Imperial Neſt againſt the <hi>Vulture of the</hi> Weſt, <hi>the ovirgrown Raven of the</hi> Eaſt, <hi>the Traiterous Magpies J<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>kdaws, Storks, Kites, Rooks, Ravens, and Cormorants,</hi> and the <hi>Larks, Nightingals</hi> and <hi>Blackbirds,</hi> do daily with their harmonious Notes' Celebrat <hi>Jupiters</hi> praiſes, for preſerving his beloved <hi>Eagle.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <head>Advertiſement.</head>
            <p>☞ <hi>There is newly publiſh'd</hi>—A Letter to the <hi>Three Abſolvers,</hi> Mr. <hi>Cook,</hi> Mr. <hi>Collier</hi> and Mr. <hi>Snett.</hi> Being Reflections on the Papers delivered by Sir <hi>John Friend</hi> and Sir <hi>Will Parkyns,</hi> to the Sheriffs of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Middleſex,</hi> at <hi>Tyburn,</hi> the Place of Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, <hi>April</hi> 3. 1696: which ſaid PAPERS are Printed at length, and anſwered Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ragraph by Paragraph. Price 6 <abbr>
                  <hi>d.</hi>
               </abbr> Printed for <hi>R. Baldwin.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>R. Baldwin,</hi> at the <hi>Oxford-Arms</hi> in <hi>Warwicklane.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
